

ANNELISE N. SMITH UX DESIGN & RESEARCH

annelisesmithux@gmail.com // anoelles.github.io

SKILLS

User Research
Usability Testing
Persona Development
Card Sorting
Journey Mapping
Content Analysis
HTML/CSS
Paper Prototyping
Mobile Experience Design
Axure
Sketch
InVision
OmniGraffle
Adobe Illustrator

EDUCATION

UX Design ImmersiveGeneral Assembly Seattle

MA in Human Development
Washington State University
Prevention Science Track
2013

BA in Social Sciences
Washington State University
Minors in German and
Ethnic Studies
2011

SUMMARY

I'm a UX designer and researcher with experience applying user-centered methodologies to identify core user needs and motivations, translating these insights into evidence-based designs. Armed with a creative yet analytical mind, I have a knack for quickly building genuine connections with others and I approach challenges with an enthusiasm that naturally motivates those around me.

EXPERIENCE

UX Designer // Dive Around the Clock // Seattle, WA // Aug 2016 - Oct 2016

Improve alignment of website with user needs through primary user research including interviews, usability testing, and behavioral observation; utilize IA principles and develop site maps/wireframes that enable intuitive navigation and increase click-through to donation and volunteer registration tasks; create new visual branding and style guide.

Field Marketing Specialist // Publicis Hawkeye // Seattle, WA // Oct 2015-Aug 2016

Devise, organize, and execute guerrilla marketing campaigns to drive product awareness and foster brand loyalty

Investigator // WA Child Protective Services // Tacoma, WA // Aug 2014- Oct 2015

Conduct in-home interviews and rapport-building to identify core family problems and make critical legal decisions under limited time constraints and in high-stress situations; facilitate creative solutions to child safety problems using existing family and community resources; create accurate documentation in compliance with federal mandates.

Site Coordinator // Communities in Schools // Lakewood, WA // Aug 2013- Oct 2014

Collaborate with student, family, school, and community stakeholders to identify core student needs and secure resources for at-risk students.

Research Assistant // Washington State University // Pullman, WA // Aug 2011- July 2013

Create and oversee implementation of data collection and analysis timeline; collaborate as author on scholarly publications; write research briefs and literature reviews to support evidence-based decision making; develop outcome evaluation plans for existing health promotion programs; design, implement, and evaluate social media campaigns for incoming students.